A Guide to the Washington Irving Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6256-p
Washington Irving Collection 1805-1857, n. d.
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6256-p
ca. 17 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase 1965 Jan 14
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Introduction to Bracebridge Hall, n. d.; AM, 1 p. (portion)
  - Mexican Portents, n. d.; AMs, 11 p. (portions)
- Correspondence
  - [ Washington Irving] to [ William Irving], 1805 Apr 4; AL, 4 p. (fragment)
    (may be beginning of AL, [1805 Apr 4] Washington Irving to [ William Irving], in 6256-t )
  - Washington Irving to John Irving, 1830 Dec 22; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to [one of his sisters], 1838 Sep 22; ALS, 4 p. (fragment)
  - Washington Irving to [Sarah] Van Wart, 1838 Oct 24; ALS, 4 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to [Sarah] Van Wart, 1838 Dec 1; ALS, 4 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to [one of his sisters], 1839 Mar 26; AL, 2 p. (fragment)
  - Washington Irving to [Sarah] Van Wart, 1840 May 4; ALS, 4 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to [Sarah] Van Wart, 1840 Nov 25; AL, 4 p. (fragment)
  - Washington Irving to [Sarah] Van Wart, 1840 Dec 26; ALS, 4 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to [ Sarah Van Wart], 1841 Jan 19; AL, 4 p. (fragment)
  - Washington Irving to [Sarah] Van Wart, 1842 Jun 8; AL, 4 p. w/addr
    (signature removed)
  - Washington Irving to [ Sarah Van Wart], 1847 Aug 29; AL, 4 p. (incomplete)
  - Washington Irving to Henry Van Wart, 1857 Jul 31; ALS, 1 p.
- Miscellaneous
  - Addressed to Washington Irving as Envoy Extraordinary from American and Foreign Agency, Envelope
  - Membership certificate of Washington Irving in Instituto Historio e Geographico do Brasil, 1839 Dec 1; Printed, 1 p.
  - Membership certificate of Washington Irving in Maryland Historical Society, 184 Jun 6; Printed, 1 p.